<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Timelines on px3l</title>
        <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Timelines on px3l</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://px3l.com/timeline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>CTO at BIMLauncher Ltd</title>
            <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/bimlauncher/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/bimlauncher/</guid>
            <description>BIMLauncher Ltd BIMLauncher Ltd develops and runs integrations between cloud software. The platform offers highly configurable and customisable workflows to be built between software for construction projects which enable data synchronization and migrations.
From the digitilastion of the AEC industries emerged a new and important concept: the Common Data Environment (CDE). Many project management solutions were developed each offering a set of tools and claiming to act as the CDE but the reality is that across a large construction project, teams of different disciplines, geographic locations and even different stages of the project lifecycle, choose their own digital tools.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="bimlauncher-ltd">BIMLauncher Ltd</h2>
<p>BIMLauncher Ltd develops and runs integrations between cloud software. The platform offers highly configurable and customisable workflows to be built between software for construction projects which enable data synchronization and migrations.</p>
<p>From the digitilastion of the AEC industries emerged a new and important concept: the Common Data Environment (CDE). Many project management solutions were developed each offering a set of tools and claiming to act as the CDE but the reality is that across a large construction project, teams of different disciplines, geographic locations and even different stages of the project lifecycle, choose their own digital tools. This leaves a broken CDE as data is locked in silos and has to be manually transferred between teams chosen solution.</p>
<p>BIMLauncher allows data to be moved from one software to another, so that tools can be used side by side (data synchronization) or a new tool introduced with ease (data migration). BIMLauncher solves the disconnect in the CDE and allows best of breed tools to be used across a whole construction project seamlessly.</p>
<p>As CTO it is my responsibility to deliver on customer requirements and features by managing the development and operations of our software. The platform is built in modern micro-service based web technologies (primarily written in nodeJS) and runs on AWS. To successfully meet deadlines and deliver the best version of our software, a deep understanding of our system architecture, functionality and operations is required.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.bimlauncher.com/">BIMLauncher Website</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Owner and Director at Strange Labs</title>
            <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/strangelabs/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/strangelabs/</guid>
            <description>Strange Labs I wanted to take my favourite experiences from the technology startup world: meeting enthusiastic people and sharing ideas, and create an environment where that could happen regularly.
Strange Labs was the first technology Meet up space of it&amp;rsquo;s kind in the UK on the high street. Alongside this, Strange Labs quickly became the top rated computer shop in Bristol.
Though the main business was through PC custom builds, repairs and upgrades, the core idea of the space was facilitating technology discussion and discovery.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="strange-labs">Strange Labs</h2>
<p>I wanted to take my favourite experiences from the technology startup world: meeting enthusiastic people and sharing ideas, and create an environment where that could happen regularly.</p>
<p>Strange Labs was the first technology Meet up space of it&rsquo;s kind in the UK on the high street. Alongside this, Strange Labs quickly became the <a href="https://www.google.com/search?source=hp&amp;ei=T2iLXvuVHYqLlwS9varoAg&amp;q=strange+labs&amp;oq=strange+labs&amp;gs_lcp=CgZwc3ktYWIQAzICCAAyBggAEBYQHjIGCAAQFhAeMgYIABAWEB4yBggAEBYQHjoFCAAQgwE6BAgAEAM6BAgAEApKJQgXEiEwZzEwM2c3Nmc4OWc4MWc5MGc2N2c4MWcxMDlnOTVnNzdKGQgYEhUwZzFnMWcxZzFnMWcxZzFnMWcxZzNQpAxY9BZguhhoAHAAeACAAVqIAa8GkgECMTKYAQCgAQGqAQdnd3Mtd2l6&amp;sclient=psy-ab&amp;ved=0ahUKEwi7-ZqDq9ToAhWKxYUKHb2eCi0Q4dUDCAg&amp;uact=5#lrd=0x48718e0bd868ffff:0xa1142d8202740a2a,1,,,">top rated computer shop in Bristol</a>.</p>
<p>Though the main business was through PC custom builds, repairs and upgrades, the core idea of the space was facilitating technology discussion and discovery. I hosted a successful long running meetup series on topics from AI, crypto-currency, and emerging technology in politics. Several of the projects started in Strange Labs have continued to develop - most notably a virtual reality art gallery where the works can be bought by crypto-currencies, a raffle based on random selections on the blockchain, and an AI based art piece highlighting the spectrum of humans across the planet.</p>
<p><img src="https://strangelabs.io/images/blog/designing-a-space-for-technology-enthusiasts-6.jpg" alt="Strange Labs">
You can see my notes on designing the physical space <a href="https://strangelabs.io/blog/designing-a-space-for-technology-enthusiasts/">here</a>, on the Strange Labs blog.</p>
<p>Sadly, the shop was closed due to the 2020 COVID pandemic and I moved to an online only business with a narrower focus, offering bespoke custom build computers for professionals and high end gaming. The Meet-ups unfortunately stopped with it, but a discussion around emerging technologies continues on a signal group.</p>
<p><a href="https://strangelabs.io">Strange Labs website</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Co-founder &amp; CTO at Jenca Ltd</title>
            <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/jenca/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/jenca/</guid>
            <description>Jenca Ltd Building on the idea of an open platform for building data, Jenca was an attempt to help democratize the building process by allowing non-technical workers found in the AEC industries to engage with open technologies.
The premise was a platform which allowed users to run compile applications at scale. These applications were deployed as collections, which we called Projects.
The platform was based on a NodeJS architecture running on Docker and Kubernetes.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="jenca-ltd">Jenca Ltd</h2>
<p>Building on the idea of an open platform for building data, Jenca was an attempt to help democratize the building process by allowing non-technical workers found in the AEC industries to engage with open technologies.</p>
<p>The premise was a platform which allowed users to run compile applications at scale. These applications were deployed as collections, which we called Projects.</p>
<p>The platform was based on a NodeJS architecture running on Docker and Kubernetes.</p>
<p>Jenca has been featured in <a href="http://www.bimplus.co.uk/news/google-ins4pires-n7ew-bim-app-platform-j7enca/" target="blank">BIM+ magazine</a> and partnered with other cutting edge AEC web applications like the <a href="http://bimserver.org/" target="blank">BIMserver</a>, <a href="http://3drepo.org/" target="blank">3D Repo</a> and <a href="http://duraark.eu/" target="blank">Duraark</a>.</p></p>
<p>We secured funding through a business accelerator in London, however the project required a significant R&amp;D stage in order to explore how these applications would work together and the investors were not willing to engage further until a solution was discovered.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker at KubeCon Europe Conference 2016</title>
            <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/kubecon/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/kubecon/</guid>
            <description>KubeCon Europe Conference 2016 KubeCon
KubeCon is the major Google Kubernetes conference in the world. I was invited to speak by the organisers based on the work they had seen on GitHub. I presented the story about how Jenca applied the Google Kubernetes technology to a new vertical industry- construction</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="kubecon-europe-conference-2016">KubeCon Europe Conference 2016</h2>
<p><a href="https://kubecon.io/">KubeCon</a></p>
<p>KubeCon is the major Google Kubernetes conference in the world. I was invited to speak by the organisers based on the work they had seen on GitHub. I presented the story about how Jenca applied the Google Kubernetes technology to a new vertical industry- construction</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker at TE&amp;CH Conference 2015</title>
            <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/tech/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/tech/</guid>
            <description>TE&amp;amp;CH Conference 2015 TE&amp;amp;CH
TE&amp;amp;CH was a technology and education conference aimed at fringe research projects gaining traction in the UK. After the success of the presentation at AEChack, BIMscripts investors invited me to give the same presentation at TE&amp;amp;CH conference. I presented it alongside the latest demo of our system.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="tech-conference-2015">TE&amp;CH Conference 2015</h2>
<p><a href="http://te-ch.uk/">TE&amp;CH</a></p>
<p>TE&amp;CH was a technology and education conference aimed at fringe research projects gaining traction in the UK. After the success of the presentation at AEChack, BIMscripts investors invited me to give the same presentation at TE&amp;CH conference. I presented it alongside the latest demo of our system.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker at AEChack Conference 2015</title>
            <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/aechack/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/aechack/</guid>
            <description>AEChack Conference 2015 AEChack
AEChack is a worldwide recognised hackathon for the AEC industries. BIMscript was invited to attend to run one of the groups, and I gave a presentation describing the lean, agile strategy we employed as a company in developing software for the construction industry.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="aechack-conference-2015">AEChack Conference 2015</h2>
<p><a href="http://aechack.nl/">AEChack</a></p>
<p>AEChack is a worldwide recognised hackathon for the AEC industries. BIMscript was invited to attend to run one of the groups, and I gave a presentation describing the lean, agile strategy we employed as a company in developing software for the construction industry.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Speaker at World Information Architecture UX Conference 2015</title>
            <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/wia/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/wia/</guid>
            <description>World Information Architecture UX Conference 2015 World Information Architecture
I was invited to speak at the World Information Architecture UX Conference in Bristol. I presented how to design web applications for people in the construction industry, specifically how to design an application which can be used by labourers on site and in the office.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="world-information-architecture-ux-conference-2015">World Information Architecture UX Conference 2015</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.worldiaday.org/">World Information Architecture</a></p>
<p>I was invited to speak at the World Information Architecture UX Conference in Bristol. I presented how to design web applications for people in the construction industry, specifically how to design an application which can be used by labourers on site and in the office.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Co-founder &amp; CTO at BIMscript Ltd</title>
            <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/bimscript/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/bimscript/</guid>
            <description>BIMscript Ltd BIMscript Ltd was a technology and BIM consultancy for the Architecture, Engineering and Construction industries.
I took the successes of the society I ran at university and moved it into the professional world. BIMscript provided expert advice and implementation on emerging technologies including virtual reality, 3D printing, 3D laser scanning, photogrammetry and modelling, BIM implementation and strategy, and cloud technologies.
Our clients included major construction and engineering firms VolkerFitzpatrick and Hoare Lea, among other clients such as FreestyleXtreme Ltd and the Foundation for the Common Good.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="bimscript-ltd">BIMscript Ltd</h2>
<p>BIMscript Ltd was a technology and BIM consultancy for the Architecture, Engineering and Construction industries.</p>
<p>I took the successes of the <a href="/timeline/ftd/">society</a> I ran at university and moved it into the professional world. BIMscript provided expert advice and implementation on emerging technologies including virtual reality, 3D printing, 3D laser scanning, photogrammetry and modelling, BIM implementation and strategy, and cloud technologies.</p>
<p>Our clients included major construction and engineering firms <a href="http://www.volkerfitzpatrick.co.uk/">VolkerFitzpatrick</a> and <a href="http://www.hoarelea.com/">Hoare Lea</a>, among other clients such as <a href="http://www.freestylextreme.com/">FreestyleXtreme Ltd</a> and the Foundation for the Common Good.</p>
<p>During my time as CTO for BIMscript, we completed a proof of concept for a large scale web platform to revolutionise the method of project delivery for our major client, VolkerFitzpatrick. This proof of concept not only won funding, but was highly received by the client and many other significant actors in the construction tech world.</p>
<p>The project, named the BIMportal, was a multi-device cloud based suite of applications which enabled all stakeholders in a construction project to engage with it in real time. We had to restructure the company in order to fulfil the requirements for funding and so we closed BIMscript Ltd and opened a new company, putting our time into developing the BIMportal further.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Co-founder &amp; Vice President at Future Technology and Design Society</title>
            <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/ftd/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/ftd/</guid>
            <description>Future Technology and Design Whilst studying in the final year of my degree, a classmate and I observed that there was very minimal, if any, interaction between disciplines at university. We were studying Architecture and planning, yet we were not once advised to seek any other input to the subject than from the lecturers, classmates and industry professionals. We both thought, given the ongoing digitalisation of construction, and the future cities initiatives, that students and lecturers involved in other technical fields may have vital input into how Architecture can be done better.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="future-technology-and-design">Future Technology and Design</h2>
<p>Whilst studying in the final year of my degree, a classmate and I observed that there was very minimal, if any, interaction between disciplines at university. We were studying Architecture and planning, yet we were not once advised to seek any other input to the subject than from the lecturers, classmates and industry professionals. We both thought, given the ongoing digitalisation of construction, and the future cities initiatives, that students and lecturers involved in other technical fields may have vital input into how Architecture can be done better.</p>
<p>To involve other mindsets in this discussion, my friend and I founded a society named Future Technology and Design (FT+D). Our aim was to encourage other multi-discipline discussion around architecture and the development of our Built Environment.</p>
<p>To achieve this, we put on a series of lectures and presentations, inviting disciplines from product designers to robotics engineers, politics and sociology students to game developers, and actively built a society.</p>
<p>Throughout the year, alongside the various lectures and guest speakers we hosted, we completed one major project building a 3D scanner from scratch. The subject was based on the interest of the society and included designing and making circuit boards, 3D printing components and learning the software to manipulate point clouds/meshes taken from the scans. We then used this scanner to attempt to scan environments and objects into the computer.</p>
<p>The society was left as one of the fastest growing societies at the university when we completed our degrees, and formed the founding ideas of my first business out of university.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Education</title>
            <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/education/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/education/</guid>
            <description> 2:1 Undergraduate Bachelor of Science (BSc) in The Built and Natural Environment from University of the West of England Level 2 Accredited Trainer for McNeel Rhino3D software Certificate of Higher Education in Computer Visualisation and Animation from Bournemouth University; 4 A-Levels, A to C, in Maths and Mechanics, Physics, Art and Design and General Studies; 10 GCSEs, A* to B, including Maths, Science, English; </description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li>2:1 Undergraduate Bachelor of Science (BSc) in The Built and Natural Environment from University of the West of England</li>
  <li>Level 2 Accredited Trainer for McNeel Rhino3D software</li>
  <li>Certificate of Higher Education in Computer Visualisation and Animation from Bournemouth University;</li>
  <li>4 A-Levels, A to C, in Maths and Mechanics, Physics, Art and Design and General Studies;</li>
  <li>10 GCSEs, A* to B, including Maths, Science, English;</li>
</ul>]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Computer Technician at Eye-Systems Ltd</title>
            <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/eyesys/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/eyesys/</guid>
            <description>Eye-Systems Ltd My first professional experience with computer systems and IT was from 2004 to 2006 when I was employed as a computer technician and advisor. My roles included a mixture of customer service and engineering.
I was given responsibility for designing and building PC systems, repairing customer PCs, designing and installing networks on site in business premises and installing and maintaining Operating Systems and software.
Customer facing duties included helping customers on the telephone and in store.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="eye-systems-ltd">Eye-Systems Ltd</h2>
<p>My first professional experience with computer systems and IT was from 2004 to 2006 when I was employed as a computer technician and advisor. My roles included a mixture of customer service and engineering.</p>
<p>I was given responsibility for designing and building PC systems, repairing customer PCs, designing and installing networks on site in business premises and installing and maintaining Operating Systems and software.</p>
<p>Customer facing duties included helping customers on the telephone and in store.</p>
<p>Though I had an interest in hardware and building PCs from earlier in my childhood, this work was an introduction into customer service which I found I enjoyed, even as a child.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
