<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link>https://px3l.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Curriculum Vitae</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://px3l.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Owner, Director</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/computerright/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/computerright/</guid>
      <description>Computer Right Ltd I was employed as a manager, computer expert, sales representative and engineer at Computer Right, a computer shop in Bristol registered under Bristol Office Essentials Ltd. My duty included all managerial roles in running a successful shop, alongside repairing and building Windows and Mac PCs/laptops and mobiles. I engage with clients on the telephone and in store to resolve computer related problems. Since starting in April 2016, I have cleaned, organised and streamlined the workshop established modern, agile working practices which have significantly helped with work flow and profitability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-founder, CTO</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/jenca/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/jenca/</guid>
      <description>Jenca Ltd Jenca was a Not For Profit company offering a PaaS/IaaS product on which Architecture, Engineering and Construction (AEC) web application developers can easily market and run their applications at a global scale. We are a community project that is 100% open source. Jenca has been featured in BIM+ magazine and is partnered with other cutting edge AEC web applications like the BIMserver, 3D Repo and Duraark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/kubecon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/kubecon/</guid>
      <description>KubeCon Europe Conference 2016 KubeCon is the major Google Kubernetes conference in the world. I was invited to speak by the organisers based on the work they had seen on GitHub. I presented the story about how Jenca applied the Google Kubernetes technology to a new vertical industry: AEC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/tech/</guid>
      <description>TE&amp;amp;CH Conference 2015 TE&amp;amp;CH was a technology and education conference aimed at fringe research projects gaining traction in the UK. After the success of the presentation at AEChack, BIMscripts investors invited me to give the same presentation at TE&amp;amp;CH conference. I presented it alongside the latest demo of our system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/aechack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/aechack/</guid>
      <description>AEChack Conference 2015 AEChack is a worldwide recognised hackathon for the AEC industries. BIMscript was invited to attend to run one of the groups, and I gave a presentation describing the lean, agile strategy we employed as a company in developing software for the construction industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/wia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/wia/</guid>
      <description>World Information Architecture UX Conference 2015 I was invited to speak at the World Information Architecture UX Conference in Bristol. I presented how to design web applications for people in the construction industry, specifically how to design an application which can be used by labourers on site and in the office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-founder, CTO</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/bimscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/bimscript/</guid>
      <description>BIMscript Ltd My first company, BIMscript Ltd was a technology and BIM consultancy for the Architecture, Engineering and Construction industries.
I took the successes of the society I ran at university and moved it into the professional world. BIMscript provided expert advice and implementation on emerging technologies including virtual reality, 3D printing, 3D laser scanning, photogrammetry and modelling, BIM implementation and strategy, and cloud technologies.
Our clients included major construction and engineering firms VolkerFitzpatrick and Hoare Lea, among other clients such as FreestyleXtreme Ltd and the Foundation for the Common Good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-founder, Vice President</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/ftd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/ftd/</guid>
      <description>Future Technology and Design Whilst studying in the final year of my degree, a classmate and I observed that there was very minimal, if any, interaction between disciplines at university. We were studying Architecture and planning, yet we were not once advised to seek any other input to the subject than from the lecturers, classmates and industry professionals. We both thought, given the ongoing digitalisation of construction, and the future cities initiatives, that students and lecturers involved in other technical fields may have vital input into how Architecture can be done better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Technician</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/eyesys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/eyesys/</guid>
      <description>Eye-Systems Ltd My first professional experience with computer systems and IT was from 2004 to 2006 when I was employed as a computer technician and advisor. My roles included a mixture of customer service and engineering.
I was given responsibility for designing and building PC systems, repairing customer PCs, designing and installing networks on site in business premises and installing and maintaining Operating Systems and software.
Customer facing duties included helping customers on the telephone and in store.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>