<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>px3l</title>
    <link>https://px3l.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on px3l</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://px3l.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Product Manager at BIMLauncher Ltd</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/bimlauncher/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/bimlauncher/</guid>
      <description>BIMLauncher Ltd I was tasked with managing product development for BIMLauncher Ltd. The product is a cloud based set of integrations between software vendors APIs that allowed data to be moved from one vendor to another, essentially the ability to synchronise or migrate data between different cloud software. This was managed through a centralised hub, hosted online. I came in at an early stage, where an initial integration had been completed and a new, more complex one had to be developed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Owner and Director at Strange Labs</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/computerright/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/computerright/</guid>
      <description>Computer Right Needing a temporary job for a few months, I was employed as a manager, engineer and sales representative at Computer Right, a computer shop in Bristol registered under Bristol Office Essentials Ltd. My duties included all managerial roles in running a successful shop, alongside repairing and building Windows and Mac PCs/laptops and mobiles.
When I joined the shop, they had dwindling business and a mediocre reputation locally. I used my experience of being in startup companies to help turn the business around and established modern, agile working practices which have significantly helped with work flow and profitability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-founder &amp; CTO at Jenca Ltd</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/jenca/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/jenca/</guid>
      <description>Jenca Ltd Jenca has been featured in BIM+ magazine and is partnered with other cutting edge AEC web applications like the BIMserver, 3D Repo and Duraark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker at KubeCon Europe Conference 2016</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/kubecon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/kubecon/</guid>
      <description>KubeCon Europe Conference 2016 KubeCon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker at TE&amp;CH Conference 2015</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/tech/</guid>
      <description>TE&amp;amp;CH Conference 2015 TE&amp;amp;CH</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker at AEChack Conference 2015</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/aechack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/aechack/</guid>
      <description>AEChack Conference 2015 AEChack</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker at World Information Architecture UX Conference 2015</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/wia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/wia/</guid>
      <description>World Information Architecture UX Conference 2015 World Information Architecture</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-founder &amp; CTO at BIMscript Ltd</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/bimscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/bimscript/</guid>
      <description>BIMscript Ltd My first company, BIMscript Ltd was a technology and BIM consultancy for the Architecture, Engineering and Construction industries.
I took the successes of the society I ran at university and moved it into the professional world. BIMscript provided expert advice and implementation on emerging technologies including virtual reality, 3D printing, 3D laser scanning, photogrammetry and modelling, BIM implementation and strategy, and cloud technologies.
Our clients included major construction and engineering firms VolkerFitzpatrick and Hoare Lea, among other clients such as FreestyleXtreme Ltd and the Foundation for the Common Good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-founder &amp; Vice President at Future Technology and Design Society</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/ftd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/ftd/</guid>
      <description>Future Technology and Design Whilst studying in the final year of my degree, a classmate and I observed that there was very minimal, if any, interaction between disciplines at university. We were studying Architecture and planning, yet we were not once advised to seek any other input to the subject than from the lecturers, classmates and industry professionals. We both thought, given the ongoing digitalisation of construction, and the future cities initiatives, that students and lecturers involved in other technical fields may have vital input into how Architecture can be done better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2:1 BSc in The Built and Natural Environment</title>
      <link>https://px3l.com/timeline/uwe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://px3l.com/timeline/uwe/</guid>
      <description>The Built and Natural Environment </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>